And, unfortunately, women have had less. And we are considered less. And so my attentions, where did they have to go? It was just ... you have to. And learn to stick up for yourself, hear your own voice. You hear the same words keep coming out all the time, and I got really lucky because I had an education. And I think if you can see it you can be it, you know? If you can see it, you can be it. You look at Pat, you look at other leaders, you look at these speakers, look at yourself, because everyone -- everyone -- can do something extraordinary. Every single person. PM: And your story, Billie, has inspired so many women everywhere. Now with the Billie Jean King Leadership Initiative, you're taking on an even bigger cause. Because one thing we hear a lot about is women taking their voice, working to find their way into leadership positions. But what you're talking about is even bigger than that. It's inclusive leadership. And this is a generation that has grown up thinking more inclusively -- BJK: Isn't it great? Look at the technology! It's amazing how it connects us all! It's about connection. It's simply amazing what's possible because of it. But the Billie Jean King Leadership Initiative is really about the workforce mostly, and trying to change it, so people can actually go to work and be their authentic selves. Because most of us have two jobs: One, to fit in -- I'll give you a perfect example. An African American woman gets up an hour earlier to go to work, straightens her hair in the bathroom, goes to the bathroom probably four, five, six times a day to keep straightening her hair, to keep making sure she fits in. So she's working two jobs. She's got this other job, whatever that may be, but she's also trying to fit in. Or this poor man who kept his diploma -- he went to University of Michigan, but he never would talk about his poverty as a youngster, ever -- just would not mention it. So he made sure they saw he was well-educated. And then you see a gay guy who has an NFL -- which means American football for all of you out there, it's a big deal, it's very macho -- and he talked about football all the time, because he was gay and he didn't want anybody to know. It just goes on and on. So my wish for everyone is to be able to be their authentic self 24/7, that would be the ultimate. And we catch ourselves -- I mean, I catch myself to this day. Even being gay I catch myself, you know, like, (Gasp) a little uncomfortable, a little surge in my gut, feeling not totally comfortable in my own skin. So, I think you have to ask yourself -- I want people to be themselves, whatever that is, just let it be. PM: And the first research the Leadership Initiative did showed that, that these examples you just used -- that many of us have the problem of being authentic. But what you've just looked at is this millennial generation, who have benefited from all these equal opportunities -- which may not be equal but exist everywhere -- BJK: First of all, I'm really lucky. Partnership with Teneo, a strategic company that's amazing. That's really the reason I'm able to do this. I've had two times in my life where I've actually had men really behind me with power. And that was in the old days with Philip Morris with Virginia Slims, and this is the second time in my entire life. And then Deloitte. The one thing I wanted was data -- facts. So Deloitte sent out a survey, and over 4,000 people now have answered, and we're continuing in the workplace. And what do the millennials feel? Well, they feel a lot, but what they're so fantastic about is -- you know, our generation was like, "Oh, we're going to get representation." So if you walk into a room, you see everybody represented. That's not good enough anymore, which is so good! So the millennials are fantastic; they want connection, engagement. They just want you to tell us what you're feeling, what you're thinking, and get into the solution. They're problem-solvers, and of course, you've got the information at your fingertips, compared to when I was growing up. PM: What did the research show you about millennials? Are they going to make a difference? Are they going to create a world where there is really an inclusive work force? BJK: Well, in 2025, 75 percent of the global workforce is going to be millennials. I think they are going to help solve problems. I think they have the wherewithal to do it. I know they care a lot. They have big ideas and they can make big things happen. I want to stay in the now with the young people, I don't want to get behind. (Laughter) PM: I don't think there's any chance! But what you found out in the research about millennials is not really the experience that a lot of people have with millennials. BJK: No, well, if we want to talk -- OK, I've been doing my little mini-survey. I've been talking to the Boomers, who are their bosses, and I go, "What do you think about the millennials?" And I'm pretty excited, like it's good, and they get this face -- (Laughter) "Oh, you mean the 'Me' generation?" I say, "Do you really think so? Because I do think they care about the environment and all these things." And they go, "Oh, Billie, they cannot focus." (Laughter) They actually have proven that the average focus for an 18-year-old is 37 seconds. (Laughter) They can't focus. And they don't really care. I just heard a story the other night: a woman owns a gallery and she has these workers. She gets a text from one of the workers, like an intern, she's just starting -- she goes, "Oh, by the way, I'm going to be late because I'm at the hairdresser's." (Laughter) So she arrives, and this boss says, "What's going on?" And she says, "Oh, I was late, sorry, how's it going?" She says, "Well, guess what? I'd like you leave, you're finished." She goes, "OK." (Laughter) No problem! PM: Now Billie, that story -- I know, but that's what scares the boomers -- I'm just telling you -- so I think it's good for us to share. (Laughter) No, it is good for us to share, because we're our authentic selves and what we're really feeling, so we've got to take it both ways, you know? But I have great faith because -- if you've been in sports like I have -- every generation gets better. It's a fact. With the Women's Sports Foundation being the advocates for Title IX still, because we're trying to keep protecting the law, because it's in a tenuous position always, so we really are concerned, and we do a lot of research. That's very important to us. And I want to hear from people. But we really have to protect what Title IX stands for worldwide. And you heard President Carter talk about how Title IX is protected. And do you know that every single lawsuit that girls, at least in sports, have gone up against -- whatever institutions -- has won? Title IX is there to protect us. And it is amazing. But we still have to get the hearts and minds -- the hearts and minds to match the legislation is huge. PM: So what gets you up every morning? What keeps you sustaining your work, sustaining the fight for equality, extending it, always exploring new areas, trying to find new ways ... ? BJK: Well, I always drove my parents crazy because I was always the curious one. I'm highly motivated. My younger brother was a Major League Baseball player. My poor parents did not care if we were any good. (Laughter) And we drove them crazy because we pushed, we pushed because we wanted to be the best. And I think it's because of what I'm hearing today in TED talks. I think to listen to these different women, to listen to different people, to listen to President Carter -- 90 years old, by the way, and he we was throwing these figures out that I would never -- I'd have to go, "Excuse me, wait a minute, I need to get a list out of these figures." He was rattling off -- I mean, that's amazing, I'm sorry. PM: He's an amazing man. (Applause) BJK: And then you're going to have President Mary Robinson, who's a former president -- Thank you, Irish! 62 percent! LGBTQ! Yes! (Applause) Congress is voting in June on same-sex marriage, so these are things that for some people are very hard to hear. But always remember, every one of us is an individual, a human being with a beating heart, who cares and wants to live their authentic life. OK? You don't have to agree with somebody, but everyone has the opportunity. I think we all have an obligation to continue to keep moving the needle forward, always. And these people have been so inspiring. Everyone matters. And every one of you is an influencer. You out there listening, out there in the world, plus the people here -- every single person's an influencer. Never, ever forget that. OK? So don't ever give up on yourself. PM: Billie, you have been an inspiration for us. BJK: Thanks, Pat! (Applause) Thanks, TED! Thanks a lot!
Malheureusement, les femmes ont moins d'opportunités et nous sommes moins prises en compte. Qui allait considérer mes efforts ? Mais finalement... il fallait le faire et apprendre à se défendre, à ne pas oublier sa propre voix. On entend sans cesse les mêmes choses se répéter, et j'étais chanceuse d'avoir eu accès à l'éducation. Si vous pouvez visionner quelque chose, vous pouvez le devenir. Si vous le voyez, vous pouvez le devenir. Vous regardez Pat, d'autres guides, ces orateurs, et regardez-vous aussi, parce que tout le monde -- tout le monde -- peut faire une chose extraordinaire. Chaque personne. PM : Votre histoire, Billie, a inspiré des femmes du monde entier. Et avec le Leadership Billie Jean King, vous relevez une cause encore plus grande. Parce que quand on parle des femmes qui prennent le pouvoir, on parle surtout de trouver un moyen d'accéder à des postes hauts placés. Mais vous visez encore plus haut. On parle d'un leadership global. Et cette génération a grandi avec une pensée globale -- BJK : C'est formidable ! Regardez la technologie ! Elle nous connecte tous ensemble. C'est une histoire de connexion. C'est incroyable ce qu'elle permet de rendre possible. Mais le Leadership Billie Jean King s'attaque surtout à la main d'oeuvre et essaye de la changer, pour que les gens puissent aller travailler en étant eux-mêmes. Beaucoup d'entre nous avons deux boulots : un pour s'intégrer -- je vais vous donner un exemple. Une femme afro-américaine se lève une heure plus tôt pour le travail pour lisser ses cheveux, et va aux toilettes bien quatre, cinq, six fois par jour pour relisser ses cheveux et être sûre de s'intégrer. Elle a deux boulots. Elle a cet autre travail, quel qu'il soit, mais elle essaye aussi de s'intégrer. Ou cet homme qui avait eu un diplôme à l'université du Michigan, mais il n'évoquait jamais la pauvreté de sa jeunesse, il n'en parlait pas. Il faisait en sorte qu'on le voie comme éduqué. Il y a aussi cet homme à la NFL -- la ligue de football américain, pour ceux qui l'ignorent, est un lieu énorme, très macho, et il parlait de foot tout le temps, parce qu'il était gay et ne voulait pas que ça se sache. Et ainsi de suite. Mon rêve, c'est que chacun puisse être lui-même 7j/7 et 24h/24, ça serait vraiment l'idéal. Et on se surprend -- enfin, à ce jour je me surprends même à propos d'être gay, je me surprends à (s'étouffe) être un peu mal à l'aise, à avoir une boule dans le ventre, à n'être pas totalement bien dans ma peau. Je crois qu'il faut se demander si on veut que les gens soient eux-mêmes quoi que ça implique. PM: La première étude que le Leadership a faite, a montré que comme pour ces exemples que vous avez pris, beaucoup de nous ont des difficultés à être authentiques. Mais vous vous êtes tournée vers la génération du millénaire qui a bénéficié de toutes ces chances égales -- peut-être pas égales mais qui existent partout -- BJK : J'ai beaucoup de chance. L'alliance avec Teneo, une entreprise stratégique formidable, est la raison qui me permet de faire tout ça. Deux fois dans ma vie, j'ai été soutenue par des hommes de pouvoir : il y a longtemps, par Philip Morris et ses Virginia Slims, et aujourd'hui, pour la deuxième fois de ma vie. Il y a eu Deloitte. Je voulais avoir des données -- des faits. Alors Deloitte a lancé une étude, et plus de 4000 personnes y ont répondu, et nous poursuivons au travail. Et que pense cette génération du millénaire ? Ils pensent beaucoup, mais ce qui est fantastique avec eux, c'est que notre génération voulait être représentée et si on entre dans une pièce, tout le monde est représenté, mais ça ne leur suffit plus, et c'est tellement bien ! Cette génération est fantastique : ils veulent de la connexion, de l'engagement. Ils veulent savoir ce que vous ressentez, ce que vous pensez et trouver une solution. Ils trouvent des solutions et ils ont l'information au bout des doigts, comparé à ce que j'avais plus jeune. PM : Qu'a montré cette étude sur cette génération ? Vont-ils faire changer les choses ? Vont-ils créer un monde où tout le monde pourra travailler ? BJK : en 2025, 75% des travailleurs dans le monde seront de cette génération. Je crois qu'ils vont aider à résoudre des problèmes. Je pense qu'ils ont les moyens de le faire. Je sais qu'ils s'en préoccupent. Ils ont de grandes idées et peuvent faire de grandes choses. Je veux rester dans le présent avec les jeunes, je ne veux pas rester en arrière. (Rires) PM : Aucune chance ! Mais les résultats de l'étude sur cette génération ne correspond pas à l'expérience que les gens en ont ? BJK : Non, enfin, parlons-en. J'ai fait mon propre petit sondage. J'ai interrogé la génération du Baby-Boom, qui sont leurs patrons, et demandé : « Que pensez-vous de cette génération ? » J'ai le sourire et je suis positive, et ils font cette tête -- (Rires) « Vous parlez de la génération 'Moi' ? » « Vous croyez vraiment ? » Parce qu'ils ont l'air de se soucier de l'environnement et tout ça. Et ils répondent « Oh, Billie, ils s'éparpillent. » (Rires) Ils ont vraiment prouvé que le temps de concentration moyen est de 37 secondes à 18 ans. (Rires) Ils ne se concentrent pas. Et ils s'en moquent. J'ai entendu une histoire l'autre soir : une femme dirige une galerie avec des employés. Elle reçoit un SMS d'une employée, une stagiaire, elle vient de commencer, qui dit : « Au fait, je vais être en retard parce que je suis chez le coiffeur. » (Rires) Elle arrive et la patronne lui dit : « C'est quoi ce travail ? » Et elle dit : « Oh je suis en retard, désolée, ça va ? » Alors elle répond : « Tu sais quoi ? Je veux que tu partes, tu as terminé. » L'autre dit : « OK. » (Rires) Aucun problème ! PM : Billie, cette histoire -- Je sais, mais c'est ce qui effraie les Boomers -- Je vous le dis juste -- c'est bien que tout le monde sache. (Rires) C'est bon à savoir, parce que nous sommes nous-mêmes et ce que nous ressentons, alors il faut l'accepter dans les deux sens. Mais j'ai vraiment la foi parce que -- si vous avez fait du sport comme moi -- chaque génération s'améliore. C'est un fait. Avec la Fondation Féminine du Sport, nous essayons de protéger la loi et de conserver le Titre IX, parce qu'il est toujours dans une position précaire, et nous sommes très préoccupées, nous faisons beaucoup de recherches. C'est très important pour nous. Je veux écouter les gens. Mais il faut vraiment protéger ce que le Titre IX défend à travers le monde. Vous avez déjà entendu le Président Carter parler de protéger le Titre IX. Et saviez-vous que chaque procès déposé par des femmes, au moins en sport, contre n'importe quelle institution, a été gagné ? Le Titre IX est là pour nous protéger. C'est formidable. Mais nous devons encore faire changer les esprits et les cœurs -- Le chemin est long pour qu'ils rejoignent la législation. PM : Qu'est-ce qui vous fait vous lever le matin ? Qu'est-ce qui alimente votre travail, votre bataille pour l'égalité, qui l'étend, dans de nouveaux domaines et de nouveaux moyens ? BJK : Eh bien je rendais mes parents fous parce que j'étais curieuse de tout. Je suis extrêmement motivée. Mon petit frère faisait du baseball avec la Ligue Majeure de Baseball. Mes pauvres parents se fichaient que nous soyons bons. (Rires) On les a rendus fous parce qu'on repoussait nos limites, on les repoussait pour être les meilleurs. Et c'est grâce à ce que j'entends aux conférences de TED. Je crois qu'écouter toutes ces femmes, écouter toutes ces personnes, écouter le Président Carter -- 90 ans, au passage, et il citait toutes ces statistiques que je n'avais jamais -- j'aurais dû lui dire : « Excusez-moi, je dois faire une liste de ces chiffres. » Il les débitait -- Mais c'est formidable, pardon. PM : C'est un homme formidable. (Applaudissements) BJK : Et il y a aussi la Présidente Mary Robinson qui est une ancienne présidente -- Merci, les Irlandais ! 62% ! LGBTQ ! Ouais ! (Applaudissements) Le Congrès votera en juin le mariage des personnes de même sexe, et c'est bien pour certaines personnes qui ont du mal à se faire entendre. Mais n'oubliez pas que chacun d'entre nous est un individu, un être humain avec un cœur qui bat, qui veut vivre sa propre vie. OK ? Vous n'avez pas à être d'accord avec quelqu'un mais tout le monde a cette possibilité. Je crois que nous devons tous continuer de faire avancer les choses. Et ces gens m'ont tellement inspirée. Chacun de nous compte. Et chacun de vous peut les influencer. Vous qui nous écoutez, autour du monde, et les gens qui sont ici -- chaque personne peut influencer les choses. N'oubliez jamais ça. D'accord ? Ne vous laissez jamais de côté. PM : Billie, tu nous as beaucoup inspirés. BJK : Merci, Pat ! (Applaudissements) Merci, TED ! Merci beaucoup !